#### Contact

304-444-7660 (Mobile) sshaffer75@yahoo.com

www.linkedin.com/in/scott-shaffer-msn-ccrn-66091275 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Surgeons
Operating Room
Capital Equipment

# Scott Shaffer MSN, CCRN

District Sales Manager

Raleigh-Durham, North Carolina Area

## Summary

A Highly experienced, award winning Surgical sales Manager/ Clinical Director with over 15 years of medical sales experience and 11 years of clinical and sales management experience. Delivering results through market growth while promoting clinical education. I have established relationships with KOL's in various specialties. Based on clinical experience and knowledge, I present myself to my customers as an asset for education while introducing new technology into these institutions to maximize patient outcomes and decrease hospital length of stay. I provide sales solutions based on clinical knowledge to my colleagues while working with upper management to identify new sales opportunities. My clinical knowledge has opened opportunities for me to speak at symposiums on local and national levels about Neuromodulation, Cardiac and Vascular health as well as offering education to institutional leaders / decision makers about the optimization of new technologies to increase productivity, decrease overall cost while providing optimal patient outcomes.

As a former Special Forces commander, RN/CCRN, and Surgical Manager I take very proven approach for success. Passion for what I do, preparation through education, integrity and dedication to my customers, and the continual search for knowledge to drive professional growth have been the keys to my success. I have been asked about how to achieve success, and I feel the best way to be successful personally and professionally is via evolution. Constantly growing, changing and learning. If you're not evolving you're dissolving.

## Experience

Nevro
District Sales Manager
January 2017 - Present (3 years 6 months)
Raleigh, North Carolina

The Superior Chronic Pain therapy That Leaves Patients Speechless

LDR

Territory Sales Manager July 2014 - 2016 (2 years)

Mobi-C® Cervical Disc

Only FDA Approved Cervical Disc for One & Two Levels

SUPERIOR TO FUSION - for two-level disc replacement

Preservation of Motion

TEI Biosciences Inc.
Surgical Sales Representative.
March 2012 - July 2014 (2 years 5 months)

Surgical device representative for TEI Biosciences.

TEI Biosciences' foundation lies in the field of regenerative medicine. The term "regenerative medicine" embodies the concept of regenerating (or replacing) human cells, tissues or even organs, in seeking to re-establish or attain normal function. This field holds the promise of enabling the regeneration of damaged tissues or organs, by replacing tissue that is damaged and / or by enabling the body's own mechanisms for repair, to heal tissues or organs that were previously irreparable

#### TELEFLEX MEDICAL OEM

District Manager

January 2009 - February 2012 (3 years 2 months)

Area manager for Teleflex critical care division that included products for: Vascular Access, Regional Anesthesia, Surgery, and Cardiac Care.

With primary focus on Cath Labs and the OR

Registered Nurse CCRN
Registered Nurse CCRN, OR, ER
January 2004 - January 2008 (4 years 1 month)
Travel Nurse througout the US

Registered Nurse, CCRN with concentration as a manager in the Cath Lab, EP lab, and OR departments. I worked within the Major institutions throughout the US (including Cleveland Clinic, The Johns Hopkins Hospital, Halifax and the Mayo Clinic) training clinicians on new products to increase case load

while incorporating new surgical devices to achieve maximal outcomes while decreasing overall surgical cost and hospital length of stay.

US Army Army Ranger July 1993 - January 2008 (14 years 7 months) Fort Benning, Georgia

United States Army Ranger.

Highly awarded.

"Never Shall I fail My Comrades. I will keep myself mentally alert, physically strong and morally straight and I will shoulder more than my share of the task, whatever it may be, 100% and then some."

### Education

The University of Charleston

Bachelor of Science (B.S.), Registered Nursing/Registered

Nurse · (1999 - 2003)